Okay,...ready to go.
Good afternoon welcome...three of build thank you for being one of the tougher tough folksy
of survive to two days of blizzards of api is...sdk is
...development patterns consider this a bit of an oasis in that in a
blazer of information today we're not going to really look a whole lot of code to be a little bit of code this is
really more about kind of the end game which is making money off of all this work that we're all
doing and having some fun along the way my name is jim maps I'm in the office marketing team
that technical product marketing folks in my whole role is around
go to market the office store
modernization awareness campaigns and that sort of thing and we really are just starting to crank
up that machine now we have a good collection of solutions in our in our
catalog one thing I want to be very clear about is...presume for a
minute to tell you folks how to make money most to you are successful folks you make money in
this business already what I'm going to talk about today are new tools in
new services to help you take advantage of the platform that were providing
you so consider this a set of disclosures announcements around new
go-to market solutions that we're going to be providing you if you partner with us
so the table of contents the first
...run through very quickly it's mostly about the state of the world today where we want to spend most of
my time is that third line addressing the customer life-cycle that is all the
new be all net new stuff and we showing you today.
So, the opportunity just kind of setting things up first of all why
we need you now if you listen to such as third-quarter earnings call we
disclosing very first-time that we have about fifty million active users and office three
sixty five commercial...closing the consumer numbers which are now about twelve million
that's about sixty two million people
...take...changes very rapidly is already out-of-date
on the on the cloud now in light of a one-point-two billion-dollar
...one-point-two billion...a person or customer business
that's quite small actually it's about five percent and even though it's doubling.
Quarter over quarter or your every year I'm sorry for seven quarters in a row we still have a
long ways to go we need you is developers to persuade folks to
move from a legacy on premises solution to the cloud and one of the things we need to be a short of is
going to be a good rich selection of extensibility and customization and
vertical solutions that they can plug into their cloud solution
very quickly so we need you to get there likewise we have many people who are an older version of office
pre two thousand thirteen which does not support this new model so we need
to persuade those people...excel is not just excels none of this another release of excel
or word or sharepoint for that matter it has a whole world of new capabilities
that you gain only by migrating to the new stuff so we need you to take these people on that
journey now we're also going to argue that you need us now.
I have all whole...to try to persuade you that so I'm going to leave it there hopefully the
next fifty five minutes will help...be persuaded of that fact.
So, don't rely on mean what I think let's look at a couple of our key
partners today what they say this is unsightly a relatively new partner on our platform
...one of the leading google apps partners actually if you go to google apps marketplace the right
their top front-and-center as a leading crm solution google
...when they joined us what they told us was the minute they built
...app...added I should say that's
...new nomenclature the bridges unsightly to outlook
their retention rate more than doubled a hundred thirty percent increase it makes a lot of
sense when you think about it because word is a data live that crm systems care about lives
and email...calendars all the data that you
...back and forth and talking about contract negotiations all those records those are
all stored in outlook as well as I am sessions so they found
...by placing the unsightly solution next to outlook through-and-through and
...the retention massively increase so that's the case where they found
tremendous value and partnering with office here's another partner this-is skylight systems as
small highest via of southern california station all very charming guy...be here because we can get
a pass for the event so pretty bad about that but he still he still loves us enough to let us
users quot he is getting customers all over the world if you read the quote
we're getting customers in singapore australia india europe they would never have
been able to get those deals of not for the office platform...the office store?
So, he has a shadow to the people in the room because he can't be here himself he's his shatter
is if I were looking at you in the audience I would tell them this is a real opportunity
...your skills change the world makes
...and hit running so he is a huge fan of this model
is nascent as it is...only going to get better so just run through a few numbers they were going to jump
...all the good new stuff that we're announcing today you probably have seen this slide if you went to
robles rel efforts I should say the internal name keep the kick-off
...are not keynote kick-off with jeremy sake one-point-two billion uses
as I said over a hundred million of them now...on android in ios
...many download we've had in those platforms highly immersive two three hours a day and office you've,
you've probably seen these kinds of number...about the number really gets me though is that last one that four
hundred and seventy petabytes of data I had to look up...petabyte actually was
a billion megabytes that's four hundred seventy billion
megabytes of data and we're only five percent down the road in terms of moving people to the
...and to think about that I wanted to figure out what does that mean in real terms if you were to
shoot attend adp high-definition video that video
could run for twenty thousand years on for hundred-seventy
petabytes of data storage facility so you could start shooting when the chinese
invented pottery take you through stonehenge the pyramids roman empire
...middle ages mainland on the moon that video would still be
play that's how big are data store already is...how much rich information is in
there for your applications to leverage and...seen this may have seen this slide as well.
To enable you to light up all that data with your solutions we want to have office
on every platform were largely done with that exercise we're still filling out some of
the endpoints whether it's mobile android ios tablet
we'repremises on the web as well as enabling extensibility
endpoints when I'm done with that piece yet but we're getting pretty far down the path quite rapidly as we'll
see in just a minute...of course creating unify and...for you to pull
...data out in one standard way one standard oslo whether it's
mail file calendar contacts all over the web using web standard tools
and protocols we also analysis week the developer program to help communicate
you with you and all these new things we're doing as well as a goody bag of stuff like a one-year free
deb tendency some email campaign tools which I'll talk about in this
demented as well as...a newsletter to keep up with all the stuff...pumping out and ever
...rapid fashion and some office add-in data as well three million
monthly users in march that's more the doubling in the last six months
likewise we sharepoint almost a million users in marge also almost doubling
in six months it's not so much the numbers themselves they're still not enormous in the context
of one-point-two billion user business the key point I think I...to leave with you is
...more than twice is about twice as fast actually as always
itself is growing so while we're starting again we're behind we're
playing catch up we're rapidly out stripping the growth of the migration to the
cloud with these add-in so the awareness in the adoption is growing.
In terms of modernization most of the things here I'm going to show you have been place for sometimes I'm going to
go through it very quickly it isn't just a nice three-story although clearly
that's we're going to talk about today primarily it's also systems integrator story if people don't want
to be...a multi tenant solution like office three sixty five they can take their on
premises up software and stick it up on a virtual machine and send it up spinning in adj or
...federated through as you're active directory they can do
...data migration services you can build mobile solutions so it's not just
and isv story but most of my talk today will
be about building things as an isv that tie into the office platform.
...have had historically over the last several years a couple of delivery mechanisms one
of the office store that's kind of the all singing all dancing solution where we have a
catalog we have licensing we manage all the commerce weekly collecting
pay the taxes we essentially manage everything for...curate the avce to make sure that they're very
high-quality and meet all the security reliability standards that we impose.
A lesser level of engagement on your part is where you negotiate
the transaction directly with the customer you silo the solutions into a sharepoint adding
catalog that's also...place for some time what's just recently been added is a
yet and even less sort of high-touch way of engaging with us
...may have a completely freestanding web solution and all you've really done is federated with as
...active directory and that tile then can show up in the office
re sixty-five app launcher so you have a catalogue of stuff that any of
...three sixty-five user can access so
...visibility and stickiness for your solution so you can go all the way from whole hard to
store?
Kind of a medium route through the side learning approach in the sharepoint
catalog or strictly to have an independent solution that is registered as a
single sign on solution may be calls a couple of office api or maybe a thousand some store facts
and figures these are all kind of housekeeping where we are today before we get to the fun stuff.
We've only been out for about two years and we already are almost ten million
downloads that's not so that we want to get that number up, you know, I would add some
zeros to that for sure but that's pretty good from where we've...most of
that activities been the last three to six months so we are achieving some kind of a hockey stick
the trajectory which is great three hundred-fifty new summations a month some of those for sure
bug fixes some of them are updates to existing solutions in the catalog
and some of them are adding another market a foreign country afar language version of an
english-language applet quite a few those are also knew things that are being added every month
...the validation time and I have the leave validation leader down right here in the
...they've gotten...down to one point three days a lot of it's been automated so even though...put
...a very extensive set of test to make sure that the user the...customer can be shorted the
...in...viruses it will be touch friendly all the things
you want to see from a really serious enterprise level solution they now have a down to
one point three days as far as a catalog almost fifteen hundred in the catalog now
about seven hundred fifty active developers again those are numbers that are continuing to
...every month and we're starting to
sign some very major players in the cloud
add-in solution space so we're going after the google part of going after the sales
...partners I mention unsightly...you sign a courses all over the place and we even
are incubating some people like pick hit me is a small scandinavian startup that
our own of developer platform evangelist and team helped to get their
...loaded is now a leading image injection solution for our sway
...getting hundreds of thousands of image downloads per month through
...integration with sway so we're billion house were incubating
...people in...also...with some of the leaders out in the space
...want to leave you with is the types of solutions in
our catalog today or third-party catalog we started out frankly we just
...to get some things in there so we had a lot of more consumer edk dictionaries
...which
...sort of stuff which is certainly valuable to the individual user but we really
...until the offerings towards the enterprise in small business so if
you look now over nine hundred of the solutions in the store are sharepoint solutions which are all about,
...collaboration
in organizational level solutions and now that we have the three sixty five story as
well you can expect to see another column on the far-right of many sas apps
in measure ad apps in the whole collection of the enterprise
things that already exist and just have to be federated or just have...calling some office api as.
Finally licensing this again
...been a story that's been place for some time we have free we have trial
you can stipulate with the length of the trial we have
paid your either perpetual or subscription and we can also charge
...you can cap that see counted a certain number so that the price...you can also do
site licensing for sharepoint organizational wide licensing for something like a
mail appetite to exchange server so, this again this has been around a while we
are making investments somewhat down the road later this year early next year to
expand the commerce components but most what I'm talking about today is in the front end
of the customer acquisition funnel and that's kind of the point of this whole talk
is the best way that we think to help you make money is first
let everyone know that this whole program exists and to get them engaged with it
to real because people don't like to change...culture changes hard
a new way of doing things is scary and part of our job is to persuade our customers
...okay to install these things...them and,
once you try them people really come to love them but it's not enough to
get the solution just in the store if you build it sorry for the
...they will come if you do two things and one is you have to
helpful the final with us in the tools I'm showing you today will
be all about how you do that the second thing is once you get them in the final you need
to engage them you need to talk to them you need to remind them you to offer them things
and to convert a trial user into a long-time and
...customer so the rest...now we're into the new stuff
the rest of this presentation is really about the things we're doing at the top three layers of the
final here awareness trial engagement to
help you take that huge world of customers all over the world who may barely be aware that
...even this thing called the cloud model the
added model into convert them to sell a buying customers so we have
four investments at the first layer of the final which is awareness
...the very first thing I'm going to show you today is a brand-new site called a this
are us are better with office dot com so without further ado.
Maybe a little...
Okay, this is a brand-new site just
one live yesterday and this is a site we're going to host.
Your videos about with your customers telling your story.
And, the great thing about this is we
are front ending the cost of the first dozen so videos were targeting the sm...space first
...going to pivot to the educational space we go out we story
...we work with the isv in the customer to create a
really compelling story and then we tape it put it up on the side we're going to localize
a videos and distribute them to our worldwide sales...marketing folks are also
embed these videos in various marketing services all across office
will be in demos will be and conferences like this and the great thing about this is if you have a
salesperson in france who has just a little bit of knowledge about this whole add-in model to some
extent is a bit daunting to learn a demo and be afraid they're not going to do it right so the weakest link is
a quality the person presenting your solution video takes all the risk out
use hit play and you sit back and they see this is quite compelling so we're going to
just walk through the site really quickly what we have here is we have a landing page?
There are there's a featured story which we can promote in demoted anytime we
...we on the whole back-end in office,
office marketing...will be a series of listings down here so right now we have to right we're just getting started
...a third over the weekend and then again we'll have six or six or more by the end of this
fiscal year in the end of june...will pivot again to edu and then we'll start going out...looking for
more scale model where we partner with you and maybe some of its do-it-yourself will still
the back-end video editing a post-production to make these really look professional so then we
move to a listing this...this is a dedicated page that every isv would get
you participates in this program again we're going to start...we're going to grow over time.
Intel's the customers story.
Customers experience using a third-party solution with
office so let's go ahead and just watch video and I'll show you a bit more about this site.
Wasn't really...great...for your regular culture...really what was important
king was two-degree work and have fun...make money so that was the birth
...demand so...the last five years we've put...business from one person
to just over a hundred thirty today...the largest implementer of sales force dot com
...we've been working with traction on-demand and for a couple years and
...very...the cloud partner of sales force another key
technologies so attraction we have this whole notion of
...what that means is under any circumstances find a way to accomplish the task
...love to say we're always looking for efficient for everything we do sometimes
...just one harder not necessarily...multiplying the number of
...how to go find...file or who has this version all this noise?
Causes...a tremendous amount of time the time that you can
...people's personal life...the key tools that we use...office
...fifty-five stack include outlook excel word
...I'd say my team spent about a third of time
working within those applications on the database with...able to find
a little...things that can...the cells acceleration
...connect sales force with office three sixty five when we first started getting ready to launch
are add-in that we connected with traction on-demand and ask them what do you want to
see they said we'll track email opens
...customer relationships our events think create and update
...and contacts they when I really have a three hundred sixty degree view all without leaving
...sixty-five the...gives us the ability to
see everything about our customers from one place it gives us the ability to get
more done less time focus...interactions moi business.
...have moi they had to do is go to office stored
...insight wants and instantly works across all their devices that we've kind of embraces
...posted no culture you...in any ideas as many...you
one-bedroom up...wall and see what comes on the challenge with...is
...are very difficult to sand to people montreal los angeles
...portland so we use technologies to get those...
notes back and forth a general welcome to our...double robots that...around here
and the autonomously meeting people and for conversation once we start using
...sixty-five...realizing...no longer needed
...super-high...machines in fact...proliferate traction
...we could actually light out any machine and have our full
operating environment with the technologies that we know-how to use I have to confidence
...inside...microsoft...fifty-five in this
...opening their environment for more small nimble creative organizations
...great technology on
their staff things will only get better and only be faster
...work-site what as?
So, not too bad we...together about three weeks
we had a very engage partner we had a very engaged customer but,
the point is this is a kind of video that you could propagate around the
world you could you could subtitle it or debit and this could be telling your story
in board rooms and sales meetings all around the world
...you have and have any sales people in market in those areas if you're willing to support of course in
the local language what you also get with the
cipher things like social so you can have viral awareness of these
videos you could have twitter facebook email linkedin the
...you also of course if you have a solution in the office store
it will link to your solution
from the story-telling pages you can go to your own partner site you can have
white papers in case studies that you can...in this site all this is free if
we definitely again it's not a high scale model yet we want to get
their where this solution becomes something that you can provide and it's really kind
...bragging rights to be able to show so that's the first
investor making is videos and social and we want to again
embed this across a whole bunch of services inside microsoft
intern on the microsoft machine
so smb people at on-the-field later edu can tell your story just by hitting play?
The second investment we're making on the awareness front increased in products discover ability
and this is something that was featured quite a bit in a lot of the other presentation so I'm not going
to wellness too much except to point out it's not just about your solution showing
up in product it's also at the store being more prominent so if you look here this is what's going
on the office outlook is going to look like
in within the next month or two both office...fifteen and sixteen
will have the store button right on the whole ribbon of the home page of course there
is also announcement...build about rolling out all the app model the
...model I should say across office for ios office online
outlook dot com consumer products for hundred-million users
so the proliferation of the added model across all of our surface is going to just
...number of folks who are learning about in using the solutions that you're building one thing I want to call
...first call to...your part though is to appear in these new surfaces you generally have to
update your manifest if you have a solution in the office store or you want to submit one you
need to use the js one-point-one in the manifest
...will not appear to assist a word of caution.
In also what's been announce at the at build is the fact that the
stores coming to the office three sixty five ten...experience as well
so right now it's showing up here you click on the waffle which is the app launcher and
...click my apps you have a toggle between my apps in the store what's coming
in matter of weeks actually is we're going to actually put a store tile
...within the app launcher itself so imagine
every day fifty million people lugging on office three sixty five
and a commercial setting and they're looking for their...looking for word excel
go what's that renting on the far in their store what is that now...course the admin of the tenet has to be want
to turn that on but for those who are open to having user acquisition
released user awareness of the store that's going to really light up awareness we
think of the fact these atoms exist again awareness is a
big part of that's the first battle is making everyone know that these things exist.
So,the next investment and this is already happened actually
global expansion as a february the office stores now available
...every market were office dot com itself is
localized sixty storefronts thirty-nine supported languages plus english so
forty really and it's not just the ui
of the storefront itself so the spanish stores in spanish and, you know, the front
...french obviously different store but it's in local currency as well in many cases so it's
...euro or...and radar whatever the local currency be not in all cases but in many cases
it follows the same pattern as office commerce in general the first...and,
mostly the new countries are in eastern europe in southeast asia
the in some continent as well as some smaller countries in europe we now have pretty much full
coverage in most parts of the world not north korea and sorry about that but,
pretty much most major markets in the world you can sell and add-in if you can sell office you can sell and
added into it but it's not enough actually to have a localize storefront
need products in that storefront to write you want to see a french language added
in the french store so we have had some success in getting
...localized but we want to accelerate that process will have hundreds of
...in these foreign stores so we are...with language me I'm
representative on the front-row here steve...happy talk you afterwards where
...collaboratively helping our partners to build
localized version is not just a matter of legalizing the strings?
And, localize in the ui of the app itself and the metadata listing in the store it's architect
in your solution such that it modular you can quickly swap a new language
...without having to rewrite the code with their part piloting and build was to customers office at
...swiss company and I
...crm and they actually localized for them and up to eleven languages
will have a quick demo that just a second so...brahms at the end of the show but
languages still out there on this on this floor and both to fourteen if you fill out a survey you get
ten percent off your first localization exercise so now we're going to see.
Of how to acquire this is going to be a combine demo here.
this is my...tendency we're going to see if this is going to be a combined demo of both acquiring three
sixty five solution but also has been localized by line-by-line bridge
so I go to my app launcher...my apps.
Again, this is not yet live-in production but we will be very soon
I click store that's where the...today get it will be in the
app launcher very soon itself and then here's a list of cure aided three sixty
five level solutions that have piloted with us to illustrate
this feature there's my mel responder app that's from the offset work team.
...click ad.
And, now it's going to install it into my three sixty five tendency that's ready registered esri
...there's the permissions...consent.
Statistic along...expected okay, and,
then it...a little bit of a lag time before shows up so...this
explain when you have your third-party solution showing up in the app launcher three sixty five again
we're fifty million people do the work every day the first party stuff will be above-the-line
...airline all the third-party stuff will be below
and what users can do is they can selectively say,
you know, what I want to put that in I want to pin that to my app launcher so it shows up when I click
falafel so you have kind of a larger pool of stuff down here and then you can pin them
...at one level up so you can quickly
launch them so let's hit refresh and see if it shows up yet?
And, there is there's a
...responder app installed and I am going to in fact pin it to my app launcher.
And, now I can launch it so I go to the waffle those
...responder app again the store button we'll be right here when that goes live.
And, now I'm...responder app and what this
ad does they keep saying happy need to say actually this is...three sixty five level so this is actually
...what this solution does is it is to create
and out of office auto respond but it doesn't in multiple languages this is where line bridge came
in so I can respond if I work across a multi-national locations I
can respond in multiple languages in set that up and they have a set of templates the generated
...out of office message in multiple languages that we have a know anything about those languages
so I pick spanish which...a little bit about...chinese which I don't?
I'm going to have the I can delay the response maybe I'm not leaving for a couple days but here I'm going
to do immediately so I can demo it and I'm going to do
...out of office in the adventure so happens to be build.
So, I'm going to do build.
And, over here and say going to be in san francisco.
Analysts.
Don't actually know the build url roles fake one?
And, there's a whole bunch of choices down here ...my back in the office...to be
back-room most likely back I will have limited access to email I will check
email sporadically I...in fact my times...since I live in seattle.
And, then, you know, what in the at in the case of my and availability please call
my I wish I had a personal system but the call him geo dude and he's going to be
...whoops to dot com?
And, then I could have emergency...the bottom like my wife
and, then I can actually own it and I'll put in my title ok and I
actually can specify a different autographs response for my
internal my colleagues as well as outside people who don't work...my company I hit submit.
...I go to the top...here is a templates that it's generated,
generated all this text using ...template and again
it's done in three languages the ones I specified there's english there's spanish
there's chinese so now I'm going to go and I'm going to send an email.
To this.
Address because I want to test how this works.
Box and I create a new e-mail I'm going-to send it to my body
And, say how you doin' because I'm from philly and I
sits send...these wait a second so I've now sent an email to the account that has the
...responder app installed and there goes
the responses thank you for your e-mail message...build
and san francisco I've limited access all the configuration settings I just made.
My...dude ...meet that guy
...contact information etc and again it's in spanish and it's also in chinese
...if in fact if I clicked on that because we are being maps integration automatic
...built-in that's not even...and you have to install it would actually show a map of
san-francisco if I put in moscow he said it would show you the exact building we're in right now all within the body that
email but the cool thing is the way they built this was
...bridge they could plug another language like that because all...did was they
send a bunch of text files that were localize and they said a bunch of json files that
had all the in all a call else to what the...names are so the gentleman martin
...a ceo he actually was kind enough to send-me a sample.
So, here's the actual json file for russian and it's just it's just basically a
Of json and you could you could do another language and install it
and suddenly have twelve language instead of eleven so those are some of the things we're doing some
investments for making around helping you localize your solution
we're also talking...about a larger partnership next year we actually provide
some investment around localization does nothing to...on that front but,
we definitely see them as a valuable partner so please go talk to...been doing this for quite some time.
So, I think I'm going to go back to my.
The lashing we're showing here and this is
not is this is more of a short-term thing.
Is the apple words this...the
...awareness investment until may...which is only nine days away we recognize not
...how to notice you probably saw these red cards floating out and all the and all the booths
...the first-floor any solution that's been published in the star between january first
and may tent or is nominated by may tenth will be considered for one of the fourteen awards were
handing out this year and this year we're doing a three sixty five solution we're doing a mobile solution
we also have a very interesting category where if isv
can actually document data lead from the store generated a significant deal it
doesn't only monetarily sniffing...but it...a new market or...open
...vertical will document those we will respect your privacy will do it in a way
...you're comfortable but we will call that out at the apple words in orlando
...the...partner conference in will also promote the solutions in the store
for a significant amount of time as well as the additional be prizes and
...be a big celebration it's another way to increase visibility of your solution so those are the
for investments are doing on the on the awareness front in terms of futures just
...to lot more going to embed...demos we're going to have been featured executive briefing
...where there's a whole getting started a set of tools when you first sign up for
office three sixty five we want add-in that experience and that's something I'm personally
tasked with doing and also my colleague up here he we're going
...also embed in visual studio have as part of the visual studio tools the ability to do
auto translation of the solutions and actually we're hoping to demo it but
there's not enough time...presentations I apologize if you want to talking about
...translation tools easier as well?
Call-to-action for awareness update your manifest to one-point-one so that
you can in fact have these show up in the new services like ios
...office online the free client anyone in the world can get to build a web back to show up in the app
...register withas your ed localize your at in talk to...bridge
...do-it-yourself and phili nominate your
...for a and apple work.
The second investment of three they were going to talk about today
is best practices and web bridges around is all around trial
so you now people aware of your solution how do you get them to use it and we have two
major investments here one is the best practices and another one is a streamline acquisition
flow so we're going to do a demo very quickly this is actually I think the most interesting thing
...the whole presentation because this is actual code to
help you make your solutions engage with customer and get them to convert from a
...to a purchase so we have built with the help of the
folks some of the folks in the room an add-in that shows you all sorts of tips and tricks and
...it's...sample code you can copy and paste into your solution has been vetted for security
and correctness there's a proper license header on it to help you engaging
you'll see in a second you want to legion from trials this
...helps you get their the sample code which is publish both on get hub now as well
as...available and behind invisible code inside the store as you'll see and
that's an additional thing we're announcing today store preview in this is something that a lot of our developers of
been asking for meaning heythe first-time I see the
...the stores when it gets publish and it looks...don't like the colors are wrong the finds
...big or whatever it's let's see I want to change it now you have to re publish it well with
the preview you can stick it in there you can...you
can designated code in the cellar dashboard during the ingestion process and then you can share out
...code just a few friends and family let them see it and say, you know,
maybe that screenshot is all...little blurry can, you know,
upgrade the quality of your imagery and the in the listing but we're going to use a previews
...communicate with you for things like this code sample.
So, let's do a demo that.
So, let's see I'm going to go to the store and.
Then I'll switch over.
Okay, so,...I am on the store now.
And, hello, how about that is a banner for the apple words on the homepage of
the store until may tenth get down and...
And, I'm I heard it's really pool sample code the
helps me a monetize my customers and it's called the...so.
...so I look for can...so.
The search engine looks around says sorry no results found
...because hidden behind this thing called office preview so I happen to know
what the code is which is code build fifteen.
...click that and boom
well are there is the sample code that only developer who is part of the
programme has been told look for here can get in the nice thing is...in
the store as opposed to outing get hub all the licensing tooling is already installs
you don't have to get a sample license you'll have to wired up to use...your own id
...use the story engine which is kind of a nice thing saves time makes it more simple.
So, here's an additional innovation used to be when you
install sharepoint and in the outlook apps or
...I should say you had to know what site to install to ziad...go to your sharepoint site
...around and look for it and then say okay this is where I want to stick it in now
...they've created a sharepoint site picker...within the store acquisition
flow so you click ok on acquire the sharepoint this will be
too not just for samples solution this will be true for sharepoint solutions in general commercial
go-to market products in the store and I can pick the site that I want to
install a to write within the flow don't have to go anywhere
...continue it gives me a by or try I'm...try it to
...kind of the whole point it says well I'm not sure you have the right to this what's
echoed again so I put that...
If I could type.
Right so there's the code.
It's now...
Ok, and, now it's install to my team site which is a site I picked in the site picker there
...it's my most recently installed solution and here is the landing
I hope, yeah, here's landing page for
...this is the sample code solution now again if you're installing
the sincere id from get hub which is fine networks to you have to mess around with a
test license we can skip that step here and go right into trying out the sample at
the point is this is a terrible
ava doesn't really do anything it's vapor where the point is so it lights up functionality
and copy and paste into your solutions that's the whole point of this thing so if you see here
agree to with hey this is a trial
...probably some cripple functionality you may have to reveal some personal information and
it's only demo data so it's basically setting up to understand so that's an example of something you can do
in the first thing that happens when you start this is now you've done the consent you've
left microsoft servers
your now serving up your code if it's a provider hosted now.
It says hey I want to know a little bit about you...pops in your ...form in
a lets you enter some personal information which is both good for you because,
you know, have some demographic data about the people who are trying out your solution
it's good for the user because you can tailor the demo or
teller the trial to the business...or whatever kind of other, you know, metric you want to you want
...a segment by it can also populate this with sample data then it pops
a form saying I like your email address please and you can make that a required thing like some of our
isv a partners actually do we can make optional so here it's optional so you
could skip it but you say very nicely if you give us your email address we're going
to send you a newsletter going to help you...tips and tricks you...the pot a bit
by telling the user if you give me a little bit information about yourself I will help you through this trial
say okay I'll do that...going to make a...address for now?
You can have enforcement of course on your and.
And, the first thing it does when I consent to the giving my email addresses a
pops a video so it basically says welcome to my trial here's how this
whole thing works so I'm going to skip it for now.
There is actually...video and now I'm in the actual experience if you look closely
it says things like outpatient follow-up in...because I remember I said I
was a member the medical community so it's showing these scenarios are familiar to me because
...particular allies a demo to who I am base of what I told during the
sign up and I'm going to create a couple of calendar events so I'm going to say I'm a I'm a surgeon
so I'm going to cut so all right.
Literally and then I'm going to.
Open that surgical wound
...it so...of...fanciful
calendar events but here's what happens I've done two things in this
in this sample and now pops little toast and it says hey
...been using this for a little while what you think and this is brilliant for two reasons number one
...start engaging them and conversation but even more importantly if
...noise and they're not happy what happens is they will click the button
...away but if they will click that by...pop...form.
And, if they if they click it right away...send the response to the
eyes feed directly such that they don't enter and angry or crabby
review so your bleed off the negative feedback and you send
...yourself and you wait for them to use it for a while you essentially have a sort
...a customer support engagement and only then later do they submit the review so up here what they want
...review they can take some right into the
review engine in the store if they want to buy who we stop them from
buying during the trial that's not a bad thing so it takes a right back to the purchase page.
If they want to learn more about it again you
have a particular video that's even context based
if they say well who else is part this thing what do they think well maybe you have.
A story-telling video you want to linked to so again it's a way of engaging the
user to assure them that there's all sorts of goodness they can...out somebody's windows.
By trying...sample and then of course the features of
the solution itself so, for example, contacts well this is a this is
...employment schedules you need to have some context stored here explains how the contact
thing work contact thing works but it also notices notes you only get up to ten
clients for free if you want more than that you have to upgrade so essentially you
tease them with some functionality but then you also say if you really love this feature
here's a way for your by the full solution then some you just say flat out,
you know, what this is a premium feature you have to upgrade to get this feature what
you expose it so that...really pulled
in...wants to engage and all this stuff maybe like I know this I do
this is fine many people starting out in this build once
in-cell many don't have this...market mentality...used to doing custom engagements statements
...work you pay you transfer the ip here you're trying to build a solution that you
get people just far enough down the path that they want to
buy and then you begin to learn because you have this engaging with
you make you get smarter about what works and what doesn't so the trial itself is like
...test launch in makes you a smarter marketer so that's the
that's the scheduler and the star preview to things I'm showing their?
The last thing on trial is.
Is simpler store a acquisition and...already saw that with sharepoint with
the site picker there's also the same functionality as we'll see in just a second with
...and it's...we should've been doing that all along fair enough we are
phili doing it but the key point is now that we have the streamline acquisition flow for
server base solutions it makes much more sense to begin to drive people
to the store through things like banner ads and
linkedin or just a button on your home page of your of your
website say click here to download the solution they can go in there on authenticated
...not immediately said go over there and sign in
...go figure out where to install it you can do all that right through the flow of the store?
Thing here here's a demo going to do this right within the body of the powerpoint.
Do over here?
Yeah, so, this is just a button which you can acquire from us
to all brand approved by
our legal folks if you want to localize let us know we can get a localized and,
essentially it takes...right to the unsightly listing in the store one thing on a point out is we now have
imbedded video that wasn't something we had before we only have links out
...video so through an experiment we discovered definitely videos imbedded drives a lot more
engagement that's something that unsightly is added and then I go to install.
And, you can see right here it's taking me to my outlook web
solution outlook web app directly it's not again making me go find it
and install it there so I click it oops...sign-in.
Ok, let's hope this works.
Because some of these things are...preview it's temperamental cookies expiring...have to renew
...that's what happens.
In production that should be the case.
Ok, so, there's the installation there's a consent.
Ok, and, now it's added that solution...have to switch back.
To my tendency.
And, I can see right here if I click on
...there's my unsightly waiting for me to
...pull in a contact I don't actually have my
in slightly account is concurrent but if it were would look for context in the
...email...pull those contact right into my serum solution to the point is whether
it sharepoint or just the word regular word excel powerpoint or it's or
it's a outlook any of our solutions now make sense
to begin putting some of these buttons right within your.
Okay.
Like okay, yeah, so, it's...
we definitely recommend you put the store button within your experience within your website.
Okay, trial futures one last thing I'm going to move on to the
final phase and that is streamline reviews we know the reviews definitely driving
...known wants to click on a solution
...store that has zero reviews it's been in the store for three years clearly that's kind of
...a lonely place so we realize we weren't really optimizing the number of
reviews we're getting we so-if...reviews in the spain site and the french site
we weren't aggregating the number of numerical ratings that's no longer true...aggregate the
number the most importantly,... longer have to actually answer of written review to
and-or...drag across a number of stars and, hid go and that will register as a...
ratings become much more common in the store and we're putting the reviews the very top of the
listings so that people see reviews high up on the page so that's also coming.
Trial call-to-action get that direct link to your
attitudes and use best practices sample.
The...is engagement.
And, just we have three quick things were going to show and I'll pretty much
takes to the finish line the first thing is our drip email campaign I don't know-how many of you
...is anyone sign up for the developer program.
Guess
...I've got a few definitely encourage you to do that one of the benefits you get for signing up
is if you don't have an in inhouse outbound
email campaign like more caddo or mail chimps these.
Guys...small nimble...it's a pretty terrific solution very super
easy-to-use that pretty robust we have
partner with them to provide a free one-year subscription to the drip account and what it
...creates automatic outbound emails...remember all those emails
...harvesting in the sample...that code you can stick in your own solution then you can
...those emails into something like drip and you can schedule outbound emails on
day one three five-thirty to say hey welcome how you how's it going
what do you think and then towards the end of the trial if it is a trial you can say peats
...buy if it's free you can also check to see if they've used in the last week or month
...pokemon say we've noticed you haven't been using it for a while why not so,
if the marriage of the sample code in the best practices solution
with drip really now gets you a true go-to market engine for
...people and it's very simply can is...in javascript snippets we're going to a very quick demo here?
Okay, so.
This is were halfway down the drip dashboard online create a brand new campaign.
...trial account I have...into call
...something and what this campaign is targeting is a particular website so-if you have a
nap on a website hosted on a website or just your home page of your actual
with isv website you targeted here so it's going to call it chien app dot
com...something up now course later downstream you'll have to actually
tie it but we're not going to do that and you can either have a campaign
that harvest...or I'm sorry harvest user activity if we're going just your website in driving by
...engaging...trial we're going to do this...this is most like the trial for a solution...
and absolution we don't have any of these e-commerce engines yes we have a trial for this
...now pretty much configured it the only two steps left really
...three steps drip millions are busy you all you have to do is
install this javascript snippet?
Into each page of your solution in that way it captures people coming in a captors
...behaviors you can do analytics later right on the drip account and then here we would have to check for the
code to make sure the snippet is...in the website but since I haven't done that in the interest
of time I'm going to finish the demo whoops didn't start a new powerpoint.
...the and go back.
To my slide where.
In finish the demo there.
So, after you install the snippet to capture analytics you then install some api
hooks you can either again just be a simple as a javascript copy and paste there is also
arrest api...asp dot net api there's one other the wrappers well that was
...and build...is downstairs least has been the first two days from drip
releasing a video that basically walk you through how to do this it's really simple
so you just basically you do two things you...the javascript snippet for analytics
and then you do this right after the user has given either contact information and that's what shoots
it into drip and you now have captured all information...campaign
engine you activate the account this is really the money shot right here it's a form
you fill out that you schedule the outbound communication you can have all sorts of
if then statements you can you can track if they respond and you can do this
from multiple campaigns effectively
triplets you with very little effort in free for the first-year take all your
samples...customers harvested with via this the code in the sample
...employment into their system and now you have...outbound campaigns again large isv
they probably already have this but for small folks this is something that they don't have in many of our
partners how to build themselves and figure it out over quite some time and some painful expenditures
we're not providing that to you as part of our services and then one of the
thing for engagement and if you
...andrew sell models talk about outlook dot com solutions
we're now enriching the surfacing of...in the ribbon post
purchase we show before the store button before purchase now
few acquire them we're going to enable you to pin your solution
on multiple tabs depending on the client whether it's
word excel powerpoint outlook is going first...in the lead you can also specify
the manifest that you...actually pop a custom tab
just for your app so the jim app has its own tab within the
client and you can have multiple commands on that I think it's up to sixty six
is what andrew said for outlook recommended please don't put sixty six commands in the
tab it'll probably get the program...so, b you want to be
...want to be respectful but the point is now we're starting to take these
add-in assert them as first-class citizens in
our ribbon right along with all of the tools that we provide first party your
...can actually show up in word excel powerpoint outlook again the timeframe
alec is going first and then the other clients are going to file in the summer and...the fall and,
we're going to focus on offoffice sixteen which is coming out in june at first but,
the point is your solutions will begin to surface again and three sixty five tenet as well as in
the ribbon very prominently the last thing I'm going to show you on engagement...we're almost at
...time is templates and we've had...for a long long-time going
back probably to office two thousand and these are things like create a gift card for
...on word and it really basic consumer kinds of things were leveraging
that technology now to help explain increase engagement with third-party
solution because imagine two thousand solutions the store like I don't know what this does and,
you know, I'm this is scary and I've never seen these before how does it work...the learning curve is
terrible these templates can help reduce that friction that reluctance to
try something new by showing people how it works so...the nice thing is
these templates don't even require you have office at all because they work in office online the
free client as well as in the rich client the paid for version or the office...sixty-five
...the...business tendencies going...do a quick demo of that.
...that queued up here I think actually...right here okay.
So, this is...to again this is a pre production...the store there's this new
blue button here called demo click on that.
Says welcome to excel online please...sign-in okay, all right.
...used to typing.
And, keyboard standing up.
So, largely into...excel online which is free and now it's installing a template and what
this template is done is an essentially has a bunch of sample data
embedded in it and it interacts with the add-in automatically in a renders is
grasses...solution so it shows you how it
works in real-life so the user essentially gets a
pre taste of how this actually works and they get a sense of know
what they can do with it if you want to learn more about it tells you how to get it how to launch it
you can whoops sorry you can click here it takes you back to the store
you can actually acquired so again templates as a way of increasing engagement
one-c users interested in aware and to get...the adopter solution more readily?
Futures the developer platform vandalism team formally called
dp now called the...we love to rename things they have they have over
the last year specifically ramped up their investment...recruiting office
partners before was all about windows in windows phone offices
step...many millions of dollars to also get them to recruit code develop
inco market office solutions and this year we told them it's not enough to
get them...actually the easier part the hard part is we want to make sure that
people are using their downloading them and they're using them so we're pushing them and they have agreed to
adopters aac api metric key performance indicator that this your data
...measuring usage...discussions about it very uncomfortable one
...if people are spending millions of dollars signing up a bunch of
find folks like yourselves but knowing
using the solution so we're taking a personal commitment to making sure that
the solutions are actually used when...required and then the store
itself is a personal goal of mine I don't think it's actually plan of record...pushing for it to make
a store much more interactive so you can respond to reviews there can be discussion forms
and there's ways to do that it's fairly low friction that is something I...on the ask
listen has been for some time from some of our partners so that's an example of some engagements
we're going to be the growing on it and calls to action link your trial app to
...campaign or some other if you have another campaign in-house already link it there
...the app commands when they come available starting again with outlook fifteen and sixteen
and may and...will this month actually...consider adding...that...that feature goes live it's
experiment right now so...of time that's for perfectly fine because I don't
have to say in the last two runs of the final this will be
investing going forward in the next year which is org
dbase purchase channel reselling we have a global reseller network we don't
really have the architecture from the calmer side...the entitlement side the catalog side
...plumbing has to be change but there's definitely intent
and work going on to make that happen we don't have a timeline we don't have exactly the rules
how it will work but we know the many people by office to a channel
throughout buying a direct as they want volume discounting they want help
and support so we say why not the same for our...reseller
of our third-party ...solutions and then better usage analytics
...things like bundles and stuff like that so this is more aspirational I want to be very clear
don't have a timeline for this we today's talk was all about the first three runs the first three layers of the
final so that's it I think I only was over by minute and I started mid-to-late...as a
...remember to engage the three sixty-five...great place to
get questions answered so stack overflow for the role gnarly stuff user voices where you
...concerns and feature asks then we have twitter and podcast we have
...mvp interviews and microsoft engineers office engineers interviewed and please
submit a review as well so thank you for your attention again I know it's been a long conference
...really appreciate you spending the time with me today thank you.